linklifting.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy - LinkLifting.com

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website. We have also incorporated important points and clauses of General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We respect the privacy of our users and thus ensure the protection of personal data by all means. In this policy we have used clear and concise language to make it easy and convenient for our users to understand how we work, and what rights they have in regard with the processing of their personal data.

**IMPORTANT TERMINOLOGIES AS PER GDPR**

Personal Data - any information related to a natural person or ‘Data Subject’ that can be used to directly or indirectly identify the person.  
Data Subject - a natural person whose personal data is processed by a Data Controller.  
Data Controller - the entity that determines the purposes, conditions and means of the processing of personal data.  
Consent - Any freely given, specific, informed and explicit consent by statement or action signifying agreement to the processing of the personal data by the user “Data Subject”.   
Processing - any operation performed on personal data, whether or not by automated means, including collection, use, recording, etc. 

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**

We collect information from you when you register for an account on LinkLifting.com.   
When registering on our website, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name and e-mail address. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.   
If you enter a query, we collect a website address you enter and keywords, if any.  
Like most websites, we use cookies to enhance your experience, gather general visitor information, and track visits to our website. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. We use cookies to help us remember and process your purchases. 

**WHAT DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION FOR?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways: 

To personalize your experience;   
Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs;   
To improve customer service;  
Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs;  
To send periodic emails;  
The email address you provided during registration may be used to send updates pertaining to your account as well as occasional newsletters. You may opt out of the newsletters at any time by using the link at the bottom email.

**HOW DO WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or access your personal information.  
All Users’ information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. Payments to LinkLifting.com are made through PayPal via the SSL connection, too.  
Your personal data is encrypted into our Database to be only accessed by those authorized with special access rights to our systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.  
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety.  

**THIRD-PARTY DISCLOSURE**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide users with advance notice. 

**EMAIL OPT-OUT**

If users do not want to receive any emails from us then they have the option to opt-out from receiving any emails regarding new updates, promotions, newsletters etc. Users can simply opt-out by clicking to an unsubscribe button which would allow the users to unsubscribe at any time. Users can find this unsubscribe button on the footer of any email received from our official email address. 

**RIGHTS OF USERS UNDER GDPR**  
GDPR regulation gives more control to the user over their personal data which they share online. Instant Views understand and support this regulation and made sure to cover all points to successfully comply with GDPR requirements. At LinkLifting.com users have numerous rights under GDPR which they can avail if and when required. The rights are listed below for ease of visibility and understanding: Right to be informed (your right to know how we process your information/data) Right to access (your right to ask us of what information we hold about you on our systems) Right to erasure or Right to be forgotten (user’s right to ask us to remove all of their personal data from our systems) Right to data portability (user’s right to receive the personal data which you have shared with us, in a structured and machine-readable format to transfer to another data controller with your own consent and/or under any binding contract. Right to object (users can object against how the organization use or process their personal information) 

**TERMS AND CONDITIONS**

Please also visit our Terms of Service section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of LinkLifting.com at <https://linklifting.com/terms/>

**RETENTION PERIOD**

As per the nature of the business it is required to keep the details of users. However, we do not sustain it for any personal gains. We will ask for consent from our clients to retain the information indefinitely or at least for 5 years. However, users will have the choice to ask for the removal of their data from our servers. Users can email us on support@linklifting.com if they want us to remove their personal data from our website etc. 

**DATA BREACH NOTIFICATION**

LinkLifting.com have not faced any data breach or hacking until now. However, we will report any unlawful data breach of this website’s database to all the relevant individuals (users) and authorities within the prescribed time period 72 hours of the breach under GDPR, only if it is obvious that personal information or data stored in an identifiable manner has been stolen or breached. 

**LEGAL OBLIGATION TO DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

LinkLifting.com does not collect sensitive personal data. Furthermore we only collect personal information for a lawful purpose, which is directly related to the website’s activities and necessary for that purpose. We only ask for information that is significant for the successful processing of your queries and concerns. We do not process any personal information without the consent of the users. Users have a free will to give consent for the use and processing of their personal data in order to receive great user experience. We do not disclose the personal information of the users to anyone else without prior consent, however there are some exceptions in which we might disclose your data such as:  
For certain purposes to do with criminal justice or the taxation system  
For processing personal data in connection with regulatory activities.  
Personal data is exempt from the non-disclosure provisions if you are required to disclose it; by or under any UK enactment; by any rule of common law; or by an order of a court or tribunal in any jurisdiction. 

**COOKIES**

Website cookies are specific unique bits of PC information that numerous sites transfer to your personal/professional computer the first time when you visit any website. These cookies are saved on your computer's hard drive and website may later use this information for record purposes. We may use tracking tools, such as Google Analytics that will install cookies on user's hard drives. 

**YOUR CONSENT**

By using the LinkLifting.com service, we want you to agree and give your explicit consent to our website’s privacy policy. 

**CONTACTING US**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below: 

E-mail: support@linklifting.com  
Web: https://linklifting.com/
